Kieran Lee Phillips

Web Developer

Kieran Lee Phillips

25 Church Street Whitworth, OL12 8QG

07882661366 kieran@kez.moe

Skills, Hobbies & Interests

Technical Skills: Since my father bought our first computer in 1995, computing has been in my blood. I have experience in a wide range of computer software and am confident that I can find my way around anything new in a short time. When it comes to development work my real world experience is in back end web, primarily with PHP, and in DevOps, where I have worked with a variety of technologies to modernise and improve infrastructure and workflows.

Tools & technologies I have experience in include:

- Ansible
- Linux
- Apache
- MySQL
- AWS
- PHP
- Azure
- Python
- Javascript
- Travis

Other Skills: As a team leader professionally and a Scout leader outside of work I have experience and have received training in Managing a variety of people and projects. My experience ranges from organising camping trips for 10-14 year olds, to delivering web project builds, and from being part of turning around a team members performance to bringing a web department in line with ISO 27001.

Hobbies & Interests: I spend a good chunk of my free time volunteering as a Scout Leader, this of course involves a lot of camping in the rain and trying to control 15 10-14 year olds, but when I'm not doing that, the role also comes with a fair amount of management, including risk assessments, planning evening and trips, and continuous training. As a Scout Leader, I have completed training to hold a Scout Association Wood Badge (A management qualification recognised by the Institute of Leaders and Managers), and receive annual First Aid and Safeguarding training.

When not singing songs around the campfire I'm a massive nerd and I love all things Japan. While this mostly manifests itself in Japanese nerd culture with Anime, Manga (Japanese cartoons and comics) and Nintendo video games, I often find myself hunting supermarkets for ingredients to cook a Japanese dish or reading Japanese history online.

Experience

Age Partnership Ltd. (The Marketing Lab) / Web Development Team Leader & DevOps Co-ordinator

2015 - PRESENT, Hebden Bridge, West Yorkshire

Having spent a summer break during university completing work experience at a small web agency called The Marketing Lab, I was lucky enough to be offered a job after graduation. A few months later The Marketing Lab was purchased by Age Partnership Ltd. a medium sized, fast growing financial services business, based in Leeds.

My work here has been reasonably varied, starting out as a newbie putting together page templates, what I'd learned at university lead me to back end web development in PHP, primarily on the company's proprietary web marketing platform.

Over time, experience in project management, both working on internal projects and external projects involving close work with clients led me to successfully apply for a team leader role.

Today my time is split roughly 50/50 between being a team leader, and heading up the web departments DevOps projects.

The work has also exposed me and given me experience in other web technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript & MySQL.

Anglo Recycling Technology Ltd. / Factory Labourer

2011 - 2015, Whitworth, Lancashire

Anglo, a family owned textiles manufacturer in Lancashire, were kind enough to offer me factory work outside of term time during college and university. Work included operating factory machinery, cleaning and loading. When required I worked on their web and IT infrastructure.

Education

Bangor University / BSc Computer Information Systems 2:1 (Hons)

2012 - 2015, Bangor, Gwynedd

My Computing degree had a focus on practical skills including modules on Java, C#, Python, object oriented programming, business practices, database systems and network design. Dissertation: Colour Calibration Without a Hardware Measurement Device, a web app to aid a user's display calibration.

Oldham Sixth Form College / A Level

2009 - 2011, Oldham, Greater Manchester

C - Electronics

C - Computing

D - Physics

Whitworth Community High School / GCSE 13 A*-C

2004 - 2009, Whitworth, Lancashire

13 A*-C Grades including English & Maths

Awards

Scout Association Wood Badge - July 2017 Awarded by the Scout Association (and national Scouting bodies worldwide) to leaders who have completed a comprehensive and wide ranging leadership course.